<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fogus/Spiel</title>
    <description>Board and card game development and thoughts.
</description>
    <link>http://fogus.github.com/spiel/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://fogus.github.com/spiel/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 10:01:50 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 10:01:50 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Some thoughts about card design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m currently designing three decks of cards and some games for them and when it comes to custom card game designs, there’s a multitude of examples for what not to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7731/17671522320_594f63a735_c_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;no&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the games for these decks are indeed fun, I personally cannot help but feel a bit of revulsion when holding these sometimes gaudy, always ham-fisted cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, when it comes to card design, it’s very difficult to beat the classics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8824/17238652173_712d868937_c_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;classic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, some modern designs have taken the classic as a starting point and added something special:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8853/17671522160_b5b25bb3c9_c_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;yes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards above are fresh, clear, beautiful and reminiscent of the classic designs.  Playing the games that these cards were designed for  (and designed around) is a joy.  It’s my opinion that beautiful cards can make a game more enjoyable to play.  Of course I shouldn’t forget function, which is likely more important.  Beauty and function in card design is not an either-or proposal, indeed they go hand in glove.  However, a functional card is a given but making it beautiful is worth a rating point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I get to the point of designing the look of my decks I will strive to make them worthy of the latter set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:F&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 06:36:15 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fogus.github.com/spiel/gamedes/cards/2015/05/19/card-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fogus.github.com/spiel/gamedes/cards/2015/05/19/card-design.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>gamedes</category>
        
        <category>cards</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>12 Icehouse designs in 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At one point this year I decided to challenge myself to create 10 Icehouse game designs this year.  The precise reasoning for my self-imposed challenge is lost to the dustbin of history (or perhaps at the bottom of a wine glass).  That said, the challenge was set and amazingly I managed to meet it.  The following games were designed by me in 2014 (sorted in order of my favorite):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fogus.me/fun/spiel/logistics/&quot;&gt;Logistics&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;em&gt;I actually think that this is a legitimately 
good game&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:c&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:c&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and as a fan of abstracts easily my favorite of the
group. I still need to work on the capture powers however.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fogus.me/fun/spiel/cydonia&quot;&gt;Cydonia&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;em&gt;I also think that this is a good game too, 
but the number of pyramids required might be prohibitive for 
some. I think that the “trick-taking” aspect is novel for a
pyramid	game.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fogus.me/fun/spiel/toripoka/&quot;&gt;Toripoka&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;em&gt;A neat micro card game that could use a 
lot more play-testing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fogus.me/fun/spiel/gorgias&quot;&gt;Gorgias&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;em&gt;My entry into the Yahtzee family with 
(I believe) a novel “battle” resolution scheme for pyramids.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fogus.me/fun/spiel/quux/&quot;&gt;Quux&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;em&gt;A little connection game designed purely to be 
a “breakfast game.” Needs more play-testing to see if there
are any killer strategies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://icehousegames.org/wiki/index.php?title=Malice&quot;&gt;Malice&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;em&gt;An Icehouse version of Alice, informed by Martian
Chess.  I enjoy it, but there is a decided lack of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cameronius.com/games/shibumi/browne-elegance-5.pdf&quot;&gt;clarity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fogus.me/fun/spiel/pewpewdie/&quot;&gt;Pew Pew, Die&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;em&gt;My version of Martian Roshambo using no
pyramids at all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://icehousegames.org/wiki/index.php?title=CarboniteDice&quot;&gt;CarboniteDice&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;em&gt;A variant of IceDice meant for Solo play.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://icehousegames.org/wiki/index.php?title=Initiative&quot;&gt;Initiative&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;em&gt;A game of perfect information that sadly can 
be very cold.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://icehousegames.org/wiki/index.php?title=Pungo&quot;&gt;Pungo&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;em&gt;Basically a game designed just to explore the 
    “controlled roll” mechanism.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fogus/spiel/master/taschenspiele/coin-hijinks/README.markdown&quot;&gt;Coin Hijinks&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;em&gt;An adaptation of Pink Hijinks for pocket
   change.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://looneylabs.ning.com/forum/topics/pink-poppycock&quot;&gt;Pink Poppycock&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;em&gt;An adaptation of Pink Hijinks to use the
   “controlled roll” mechanism.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing earth-shattering for sure, but all in all not too bad IMO.  There are a few games on this list that I think I can see myself (and others hopefully) actually enjoying.  This to me is a success.  Additionally, I learned some valuable lessons over the past year that I’d like to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;game-ideas-are-worthless&quot;&gt;Game ideas are worthless&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past year I probably thought of many dozens of Icehouse game ideas, that didn’t turn into games.  That is, there’s a huge distinction between coming up with an idea for a game and actually creating a game that anyone would want to play.  Additionally, once you’ve come up with an idea that may be playable, there’s no guarantee that anyone will want to play it.  Even further, even if you come up with an idea that someone might want to play then play-testing might highlight some fatal flaws or, at best, sticking points.  By this I mean that I’ve come up with plenty of other pyramid games…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Karankaron: Zendo, but for sound&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pedestal: a blind bidding game&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Egyptian Whist: a(nother) pyramid trick-taking game&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pyrametto: Coloretto, but for pyramids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hollywood Babylon: Babylon, but for pyramids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Helmet: a 2p abstract checkers-like&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Panopticon: a 2p abstract racing game&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Kamisado-like using the “controlled roll”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minimax: a 2p engine-building game&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A tile-laying game using pyramids and Iota cards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and many others not worth mentioning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…but in every case writing out the rules and/or play-testing exposed some deep flaw (boring being the most prevalent).  Therefore, it struck me that ideas alone are worthless and when they turn out to have been bad from the start they should be thrown away.  More will pop up to replace them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you’ll notice that about half of the games listed are derivative.  One thing that I’ve found is that it’s super-easy to take a game that already exists and “adapt” it to pyramids.  However, often I’ve found that the vehicle of the pyramids doesn’t always fit the original game.  Instead, either the derivation doesn’t work at all or the pyramids themselves inform a mutation of the original design to the extent that it’s practically a new game (e.g. Malice above).  I think that this is likely the most important lesson that I’ve learned in the past year.  That is, if you’re designing an Icehouse game then listen to the pyramids… they’ll help guide you, and wow are they lovely guides indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;play-testing-is-a-pain-for-all-involved&quot;&gt;Play-testing is a pain for all involved&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t harp on this point too much, but I will say a few words.  First, I have a problem with play-testing.  That is, I always feel very timid asking someone to play my own designs.  I always feel like I’m burdening them in some way.  Thankfully, I have two awesome kids who’re always willing to play Daddy’s games, no matter how bad they are.  Even more lucky for me is that they are not shy about shooting down my designs when they are truly boring.  That said, I still have a hard time asking people outside of my sphere of influence to help me to play-test.  I’m getting better, but it’s not easy even after a year.  This is my own psychosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-rules-is-hard&quot;&gt;Writing rules is hard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve written a few books and so when it was time to start writing rules for these games I was confident.  I was quickly humbled.  Of this entire process I still think that writing lucid rules for even the most simple of games is damn hard.  I’m still not sure that I’m even risen to the level of mediocre in this regard.  However, I’ve found time and time again that writing down rules, even very early on, is a great way to find problems in the design itself.  A few times (and more as I got more experience) the act of simplifying the words used to express the rules led to the simplification of the designs themselves.  In fact, I plan to go back to the earliest designs and simplify the rules in hopes that I can find opportunities to simplify the games themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-in-doubt-volcano-scoring&quot;&gt;When in doubt… Volcano scoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost as hard as writing rules is coming up with fair scoring mechanisms.  Indeed, devising solid scoring is directly antithetical to having a problem with asking people to play-test your games.  That is, very often (or so I’ve read) scoring mechanisms are finely tuned via a piece-wise change process occurring over the course of many many many play-tests.  None of my designs have gone through a process like this.  Thankfully for me Volcano scoring already exists, and it usually works right out of the box, it’s simple, and has been in hard rotation in pyramid games since circa the year 2000.  Perhaps when/if these games get more plays I’ll move away from Volcano scoring in those that use it, but for now I consider it a nice starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, thanks for reading.  I hope that by sharing my experiences I’ve motivated you to set a similar goal yourself, or at least to give my games a shot. :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the rules for these games are found on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://fogus.github.io/spiel/designs/&quot;&gt;designs page&lt;/a&gt;.  Feedback at &lt;code&gt;me -at- fogus -dot- me&lt;/code&gt; is always welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:F&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:c&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Thanks to its heavy borrowing from &lt;a href=&quot;http://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/19916/cups&quot;&gt;Cups&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:c&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 03:36:15 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fogus.github.com/spiel/gamedes/icehouse/2014/12/30/12-icehouse-games.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fogus.github.com/spiel/gamedes/icehouse/2014/12/30/12-icehouse-games.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>gamedes</category>
        
        <category>icehouse</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New game design: Quux</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quux&lt;/em&gt; is a Looney Pyramids connection game for two players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game requires a 4x4 game board and two mono-colored pyramid stashes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules are on my personal site at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fogus.me/fun/spiel/quux/&quot;&gt;http://www.fogus.me/fun/spiel/quux/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please consider trying it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:F&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 05:36:15 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://fogus.github.com/spiel/gamedes/game/2014/12/19/quux.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fogus.github.com/spiel/gamedes/game/2014/12/19/quux.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>gamedes</category>
        
        <category>game</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New game design: Toripoka</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Toripoka is a set-collecting, bluffing card game for 2 players based loosely on Three Card Poker played with a truncated deck. The game takes place over a series of rounds, each played to determine the winner of one or both of the pyramids available for capture. Pyramids are captured by players building the best possible three-card Poker hands given three personal cards and two exposed public cards. The player who captures the most points when the pyramids run out wins the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fogus/spiel/master/pyramidenspiel/toripoka/graphics/the-deck.png&quot; alt=&quot;the-deck&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game requires a deck of playing cards and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.looneylabs.com/Treehouse&quot;&gt;Treehouse set&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules are on the Icehouse games wiki at &lt;a href=&quot;http://icehousegames.org/wiki/index.php?title=Toripoka&quot;&gt;http://icehousegames.org/wiki/index.php?title=Toripoka&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please consider trying it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:F&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 00:36:15 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fogus.github.com/spiel/gamedes/game/2014/10/27/toripoka.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fogus.github.com/spiel/gamedes/game/2014/10/27/toripoka.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>gamedes</category>
        
        <category>game</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rules Avoidance Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An activity that I’ve found useful for thinking of game designs is to avoid reading rules.  This seems counter-intuitive since an understanding of the possibilities in the domain of game rules seems critical in growing as a game designer.  While I definitely think this is true, active rules avoidance has helped me to generate some interesting design paths.  Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;avoid-reading-the-rules-at-all-costs&quot;&gt;Avoid reading the rules at all costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I found an interesting looking game at the thrift store named &lt;a href=&quot;http://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/21777/number-rings&quot;&gt;Ring-A-Round&lt;/a&gt; and picked it up on a whim for a buck.  Upon opening the sealed lid I was presented with the following scene:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2944/15370639186_5fc3e9353b_c_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;whatamthis&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look closely at the image you’ll notice there are dice.  However, my purchase didn’t have any dice, nor did it have any rules – all that it had were a bunch of rings and a board with four hex3 playing areas on it, where each cell contains a number on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given only this information ask yourself: how do I play this game?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rules-avoidance-design-rad&quot;&gt;Rules Avoidance Design (RAD)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the core of &lt;em&gt;Rules Avoidance Design&lt;/em&gt;, aka. &lt;em&gt;RAD&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than run off and download the rules from BGG, I instead tinkered around with some ideas about what these components were saying to me about this game.  There were numbers on the hex cells, but after trying to noodle through that aspect for a while I decided to ignore them – they weren’t speaking to me, if you catch my drift.  Instead, I envisioned a 2-player game similar to &lt;a href=&quot;http://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/68199/catchup&quot;&gt;Catchup&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://boardgamegeek.com/article/16478892#16478892&quot;&gt;Mures rule simplification in place&lt;/a&gt; and each player controlling two different colors.  The game is played on all four of the hex areas and groups can span across multiple areas along adjacent edge cells.  Finally, the colored center squares are free cells for the color listed.  But what about that big pit in the middle of the board?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s for your drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game is not only fun, it’s practical!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how well, does this game play?  In my head it seems pretty fun, but I’ve not gotten it to a table yet.  That said, I looked up the actual rules for Ring-A-Round and I feel that at this moment I would rather play my fictitious game on this board than the actual game designed for it.  Granted, there are some holes in my design that I’ve yet to rectify, so your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finis&quot;&gt;Finis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve performed this process numerous times in the past and while it’s rare that a new game is discovered, it’s always a fun activity.  I have no illusions about a future game design career and anything that I do in this realm is done in the spirit of personal enrichment.  So far, I’ve found &lt;em&gt;RAD&lt;/em&gt; to be a wonderful way to stimulate the neurons of the brain dedicated to game design.  I doubt that this idea is new to veteran designers, but I hope that at least the name will catch on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:F&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 08:36:15 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fogus.github.com/spiel/design/2014/09/29/rules-avoidance-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fogus.github.com/spiel/design/2014/09/29/rules-avoidance-design.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New game design: Pidan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pidan&lt;/strong&gt; is a game of pyramid construction for two players using a Das Spiel set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each player starts with 10 dice that form the values available for play.  The game consists of alternating turns where players can take one of three possible actions: infection, placement, or passing.  An infection is the act of swapping two or more dice for one of an opponent’s dice.  A placement is the act of putting a die onto the dice pyramid according to a set of specific rules.  A player can only pass if they’ve run out of dice to play before the other player has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an important aspect of Pidan that the players are ultimately responsible for placing all of the dice in their nest onto the pyramid, including those belonging to their opponent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When all of the dice have been placed onto the pyramid the players sum the points showing to determine the scores for each side. The player with the highest total on the majority of sides wins the game.  Ties are broken by awarding the player whose die resides in the innermost cell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about how to play, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fogus.me/fun/spiel/pidan&quot;&gt;Pidan rules&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:F&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 23:36:15 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fogus.github.com/spiel/game/2014/09/03/pidan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fogus.github.com/spiel/game/2014/09/03/pidan.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>game</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to open source game design.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a blog about my adventures in board and card game design.  I will tend to focus on games of abstract strategy and card games, but I’ll mix it up a bit if the mood strikes.  I’ll also post occassionally about the ideas behind game design.  That said, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fogus/spiel/wiki&quot;&gt;my raw game design notes will be kept on my wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing about this blog is that it’s the next step in my attempt to make my game design efforts open.  I wrote about this a bit in a blog post entitled &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.fogus.me/2013/10/31/open-source-boardcarddice-game-design/&quot;&gt;Open Source Game Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, but the culmination of that initial brain-dump exists here.  Additionally, I work through my designs on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com/fogus/spiel&quot;&gt;Spiel Github repository&lt;/a&gt;.  Naturally, my designs can only become viable through play-testing, so if you’re interested in playing then please do so.  I will respond to feedback &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fogus/spiel/issues&quot;&gt;on my Spiel discussion/issues system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you wish to follow along then please do subscribe to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://fogus.github.io/spiel/feed.xml&quot;&gt;game design RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;. I’m a rank amateur at this, so my explorations will be open for all to see.  Feedback is always welcomed at my email address me -at- fogus -dot- me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:F&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 04:36:15 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fogus.github.com/spiel/meta/2014/08/29/welcome.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fogus.github.com/spiel/meta/2014/08/29/welcome.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>meta</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
