<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fogus/Spiel</title>
    <description>Board and card game development and thoughts.
</description>
    <link>http://fogus.github.com/spiel/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://fogus.github.com/spiel/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 16:36:57 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 16:36:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>New game design: Toripoka</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Toripoka is a set-collecting, bluffing card game for 2 players based loosely on Three Card Poker played with a truncated deck. The game takes place over a series of rounds, each played to determine the winner of one or both of the pyramids available for capture. Pyramids are captured by players building the best possible three-card Poker hands given three personal cards and two exposed public cards. The player who captures the most points when the pyramids run out wins the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fogus/spiel/master/pyramidenspiel/toripoka/graphics/the-deck.png&quot; alt=&quot;the-deck&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game requires a deck of playing cards and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.looneylabs.com/Treehouse&quot;&gt;Treehouse set&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules are on the Icehouse games wiki at &lt;a href=&quot;http://icehousegames.org/wiki/index.php?title=Toripoka&quot;&gt;http://icehousegames.org/wiki/index.php?title=Toripoka&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please consider trying it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:F&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 00:36:15 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fogus.github.com/spiel/gamedes/game/2014/10/27/toripoka.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fogus.github.com/spiel/gamedes/game/2014/10/27/toripoka.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>gamedes</category>
        
        <category>game</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rules Avoidance Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An activity that I’ve found useful for thinking of game designs is to avoid reading rules.  This seems counter-intuitive since an understanding of the possibilities in the domain of game rules seems critical in growing as a game designer.  While I definitely think this is true, active rules avoidance has helped me to generate some interesting design paths.  Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;avoid-reading-the-rules-at-all-costs&quot;&gt;Avoid reading the rules at all costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I found an interesting looking game at the thrift store named &lt;a href=&quot;http://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/21777/number-rings&quot;&gt;Ring-A-Round&lt;/a&gt; and picked it up on a whim for a buck.  Upon opening the sealed lid I was presented with the following scene:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2944/15370639186_5fc3e9353b_c_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;whatamthis&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look closely at the image you’ll notice there are dice.  However, my purchase didn’t have any dice, nor did it have any rules – all that it had were a bunch of rings and a board with four hex3 playing areas on it, where each cell contains a number on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given only this information ask yourself: how do I play this game?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rules-avoidance-design-rad&quot;&gt;Rules Avoidance Design (RAD)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the core of &lt;em&gt;Rules Avoidance Design&lt;/em&gt;, aka. &lt;em&gt;RAD&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than run off and download the rules from BGG, I instead tinkered around with some ideas about what these components were saying to me about this game.  There were numbers on the hex cells, but after trying to noodle through that aspect for a while I decided to ignore them – they weren’t speaking to me, if you catch my drift.  Instead, I envisioned a 2-player game similar to &lt;a href=&quot;http://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/68199/catchup&quot;&gt;Catchup&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://boardgamegeek.com/article/16478892#16478892&quot;&gt;Mures rule simplification in place&lt;/a&gt; and each player controlling two different colors.  The game is played on all four of the hex areas and groups can span across multiple areas along adjacent edge cells.  Finally, the colored center squares are free cells for the color listed.  But what about that big pit in the middle of the board?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s for your drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game is not only fun, it’s practical!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how well, does this game play?  In my head it seems pretty fun, but I’ve not gotten it to a table yet.  That said, I looked up the actual rules for Ring-A-Round and I feel that at this moment I would rather play my fictitious game on this board than the actual game designed for it.  Granted, there are some holes in my design that I’ve yet to rectify, so your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finis&quot;&gt;Finis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve performed this process numerous times in the past and while it’s rare that a new game is discovered, it’s always a fun activity.  I have no illusions about a future game design career and anything that I do in this realm is done in the spirit of personal enrichment.  So far, I’ve found &lt;em&gt;RAD&lt;/em&gt; to be a wonderful way to stimulate the neurons of the brain dedicated to game design.  I doubt that this idea is new to veteran designers, but I hope that at least the name will catch on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:F&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 08:36:15 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fogus.github.com/spiel/design/2014/09/29/rules-avoidance-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fogus.github.com/spiel/design/2014/09/29/rules-avoidance-design.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New game design: Pidan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pidan&lt;/strong&gt; is a game of pyramid construction for two players using a Das Spiel set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each player starts with 10 dice that form the values available for play.  The game consists of alternating turns where players can take one of three possible actions: infection, placement, or passing.  An infection is the act of swapping two or more dice for one of an opponent’s dice.  A placement is the act of putting a die onto the dice pyramid according to a set of specific rules.  A player can only pass if they’ve run out of dice to play before the other player has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an important aspect of Pidan that the players are ultimately responsible for placing all of the dice in their nest onto the pyramid, including those belonging to their opponent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When all of the dice have been placed onto the pyramid the players sum the points showing to determine the scores for each side. The player with the highest total on the majority of sides wins the game.  Ties are broken by awarding the player whose die resides in the innermost cell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about how to play, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fogus.me/fun/spiel/pidan&quot;&gt;Pidan rules&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:F&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 23:36:15 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fogus.github.com/spiel/game/2014/09/03/pidan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fogus.github.com/spiel/game/2014/09/03/pidan.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>game</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to open source game design.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a blog about my adventures in board and card game design.  I will tend to focus on games of abstract strategy and card games, but I’ll mix it up a bit if the mood strikes.  I’ll also post occassionally about the ideas behind game design.  That said, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fogus/spiel/wiki&quot;&gt;my raw game design notes will be kept on my wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing about this blog is that it’s the next step in my attempt to make my game design efforts open.  I wrote about this a bit in a blog post entitled &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.fogus.me/2013/10/31/open-source-boardcarddice-game-design/&quot;&gt;Open Source Game Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, but the culmination of that initial brain-dump exists here.  Additionally, I work through my designs on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com/fogus/spiel&quot;&gt;Spiel Github repository&lt;/a&gt;.  Naturally, my designs can only become viable through play-testing, so if you’re interested in playing then please do so.  I will respond to feedback &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fogus/spiel/issues&quot;&gt;on my Spiel discussion/issues system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you wish to follow along then please do subscribe to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://fogus.github.io/spiel/feed.xml&quot;&gt;game design RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;. I’m a rank amateur at this, so my explorations will be open for all to see.  Feedback is always welcomed at my email address me -at- fogus -dot- me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:F&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 04:36:15 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fogus.github.com/spiel/meta/2014/08/29/welcome.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fogus.github.com/spiel/meta/2014/08/29/welcome.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>meta</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
